<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4314</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">3. History</dc:title>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Books
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.01
Jones, R.T. 2021. The prospect of reconstructing ancient battlefields in the 21st Century: a case study using the Battle of Plataea (479 B.C.E.). PhD. Diss. Newcastle University (Australia).
https://nova.newcastle.edu.au/vital/access/manager/Repository/uon:36249
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.02
Konecny, A. and N. Sekunda (eds). 2022. The Battle of Plataia 479 BC. Vienna.
(ISBN 9783851612714)
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.03
Pirenne-Delforge, V. and G. Pironti. 2022. The Hera of Zeus. Intimate Enemy, Ultimate Spouse. Translated by Raymond Geuss. Cambridge. (esp. pp. 96–106)
(ISBN 9781108888479)
&amp;nbsp;
Articles
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.04
Brambilla, A. 2019. “Migrants, Warfare, and Social Promotion in Classical Greece.” Rationes Rerum 13: 63–77.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.05
Breglia, L. 2020. “Mythic Traditions of Euboea and Boeotia in the Archaic Age.” In T.E. Cinquantaquattro and M. D’Acunto (eds), Euboica II. Pithekoussai and Euboea between East and West, vol. I. Aion Annali Di Archeologia E Storia Antica Nuova Seria 27: 187–210.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.06
Carli, A. 2022. “ἦσαν δὲ οὐδὲ ἀδύνατοι, ὡς Λακεδαιμόνιοι, πολιορκεῖν. Gli Spartani e l’assedio di Platea.” Nuova Antalogia Militare. Revista Interdisciplinare della Societá Italiana di Storia Militare 10: 31–77.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.07
Gaebel, R. 2022. “The Boiotian Cavalry.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 243–247.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.08
Gray, B. 2022. “Civic and Counter-Civic Cosmopolitanism Diodorus, Strabo and the Later Hellenistic Polis” In J. König and N. Wiater (eds), Late Hellenistic Greek Literature in Dialogue. Cambridge: 149–177.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.09
Hatzopoulos, M. B. 2021. “Une nouvelle fête macédonienne dans une inscription de Kibyra.” Tekmeria 16: 1–18.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.10
Intrieri, M. 2021. “La philia interstatale tra eunoia, pistis e utile in Isocrate.” Ὅρμος 13: 56–91.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.11
Jung, M. 2022. “Plataiai: Das Scheitern einer Heldenstadt im fünften Jahrhundert v. Chr.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 263–270.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.12
Konecny, A. 2022. “The Road to Plataia.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 9–12.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.13
Konecny, A. 2022. “The Battle of Plataiaei. Topography and Tactics.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 167–210.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.14
Konijnendijk, R. and P.M. Bardunias. 2022. “The Face of Battle at Plataia.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 211–242.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.15
Macgregor Morris, I. 2022. “Xerxes: Ideology and Practice.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 13–70.
2022.1.3.16
Macgregor Morris, I. 2022. “Pausanias, Best of Men: Politics, Propaganda and, Memory.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 79–132.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.17
Macgregor Morris, I. 2022. “Aristeides the Just?” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 133–151.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.18
Nielsen, Th. H. 2021. “I Zeus’ navn? Et essay om hellig krig i det klassike Grækenland.” Aigis 21.2: 1–43.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.19
Nikoloska, A. 2011. “Pagan monotheism and the cult of Zeus Hypsiistos.” Ziva Antika 61.1-2: 117–127.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.20
Oikonomedes, Al. N. 2019. “ΆΛIA NYMΦH: The City-Goddess of the Port of Oropos, and the Athletic Games Commemorating its First Settlers.” The Ancient World 50: 3–5.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.21
Patay-Horváth, A. 2022. “Commemorating the Victory.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 249–262.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.22
Sekunda, N. 2022. “Greek Logistics at Plataiaei and Strategical Planning during the Third Invasion of Greece (480–479 BC).” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 153–166.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.23
Squillace, G. 2020. “Considerazioni sull’identità di Cefisodoro (FGrHist 112 = BNJ 112): retore ateniese o storico tebano?” Athenaeum 108.2: 375–389.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.24
Vanotti, G. 2018. “Cimone a Tanagra e nel dopo Tanagra.” Rationes Rerum 12: 35–67.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.25
Wiesehöfer, J. 2022. “Mardonios.” In A. Konecny and N. Sekunda (eds), The Battle of Plataiai 479 BC. Vienna: 71–78.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.26
Wu, G. 2021. “The metropolitan and the Theban silk industry: a hypothetical reconstruction.” Byzantine and Modern Greek Studies 46.1: 64–80.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.27
Wu, G. 2022. “The myth of phocaicus: new evidence on the silk industry in Byzantine Central Greece.” Mediterranean Historical Review 36.1: 43–61.
&amp;nbsp;
Reviews
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.28
Beck, H. 2020. Localism and the Ancient Greek City-State (502.1.02). Reviewed by: N. Genis, 2022. Classical Philology 117.1: 220–224.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.29
Dmitriev, S. 2021. The Orator Demades. Classical Greece Reimagined through Rhetoric. Reviewed by: G. Squillace, 2022. Sehepunkte 22.3.
&amp;nbsp;
2022.1.3.30
Funke, P. and M. Haake (eds). 2013. Greek Federal States and their Sanctuaries: Identities and Integration (Tereisias previous series: 441.1.05). Reviewed by: K. Vlassopoulos, 2015. Scripta Classica Israelica 34: 247–249.2022.1.3.04
&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Teiresias Journal Online</dc:publisher>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Teiresias Journal Online</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-07-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/tjo/article/view/4314</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Teiresias Journal Online; Bd. 1 Nr. 1 (2022): Teiresias Journal Online</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Teiresias Journal Online; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2022): Teiresias Journal Online</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.17879/tjo-2022-vol1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/tjo/article/view/4314/4372</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/tjo/article/view/4314/4373</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>