<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>3146</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">A Landscape Lullaby? The Function of (Post-) Pastoral Elements in Kazuo Ishiguro's Never Let Me Go</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Musial, Lisa</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Never Let Me Go</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Kazuo Ishiguro</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Literary Studies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">pastoral</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">post-pastoral elements</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">nature in literature</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">postmodern literature</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">anti-pastoral</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">dystopia</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Published in 2005, Kazuo Ishiguro’s novel Never Let Me Go presents a vision of a society where clones are raised to donate their vital organs. Because of the dystopian elements in the narration, one might expect a setting in a futuristic environment. Instead, the story takes place mainly in pastoral visions of the English countryside. This distinct setting creates a stark contrast to the characters’ harsh reality, which is gradually revealed throughout the narrative. In this article, I argue that the novel complicates the pastoral and offers new perspectives on the relationship of humans and nature by incorporating post-pastoral elements. In order to investigate the contrast between the dystopian reality and its peaceful setting, the pastoral initially provides a useful lens. The concept is an “ancient cultural tool” often found in literature, which is used to express humanity’s relationship to the land and natural surroundings (Gifford, “Post-Pastoral” 15; “Reading Strategies” 45). It is extended by approaches like the anti-pastoral and the post-pastoral. By primarily following Terry Gifford’s theoretical understandings, I will use these concepts for an analysis of the novel’s descriptions of nature, choice of language and narrative structure. I will mainly focus on the depiction of Hailsham, a boarding school for clones, because this offers insights into the characters’ ways of handling their fate and the importance of their childhood&amp;nbsp;surroundings throughout their lives.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">English Department, University of Münster</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/satura/article/view/3146</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.17879/satura-2018-3146</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Satura; Bd. 1 (2018); 57-62</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Satura; Vol. 1 (2018); 57-62</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2701-0201</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2629-4923</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/satura/article/view/3146/3121</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>urn:nbn:de:hbz:6:3-satura-2018-31215</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Lisa Musial</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>