<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>2616</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Deposits of disease-associated alpha-synuclein may be present in the dura mater in Lewy body disorders: implications for potential inadvertent transmission by surgery</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Gelpi, Ellen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Visanji, Naomi P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hönigschnabl, Selma</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Reiner, Angelika</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Fischer, Peter</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Lang, Anthony</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Budka, Herbert</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kovacs, Gabor G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Alpha-synuclein</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Dura mater</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Lymphatic drainage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Prion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Propagation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Transmission</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Deposition of alpha-synuclein in the brain is a hallmark of Lewy body disorders. Alpha-synuclein has been considered to show prion-like properties. Prion diseases can be transmitted by the transplantation of cadaveric dura mater causing iatrogenic Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease. Recent observations of amyloid-β deposition in dural grafts support the seeding properties of amyloid-β. Here we assessed the presence of alpha-synuclein in dura mater samples as a potential transmissible seed source. We immunostained 32 postmortem dura mater samples; 16 cases with Lewy-body disorder (LBD) showing different pathology stages and 16 non-LBD cases for phosphorylated (Ser129) and disease-associated (5G4) alpha-synuclein. Disease-associated alpha-synuclein aggregates were identified in intradural nerve fibres and associated with a vessel in a single LBD-Braak stage 4 case. We conclude that alpha-synuclein is detectable, although rarely, in dura mater samples in patients with LBD. The risk of potential transmissibility of dural alpha-synuclein deserves assessment by complementary experimental studies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Prof. Dr. Werner Paulus, University of Muenster, Institute of Neuropathology</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-02-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Original Paper</dc:type>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/fnp/article/view/2616</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.17879/freeneuropathology-2020-2616</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Free Neuropathology; Bd. 1 (2020); 6</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Free Neuropathology; Vol. 1 (2020); 6</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2699-4445</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/fnp/article/view/2616/2522</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/fnp/article/view/2616/2518</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>urn:nbn:de:hbz:6:3-freeneuropathology-2020-25227</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>urn:nbn:de:hbz:6:3-freeneuropathology-2020-25182</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Ellen Gelpi, Naomi P. Visanji, Selma Hönigschnabl, Angelika Reiner, Peter Fischer, Anthony Lang, Herbert Budka, Gabor G. Kovacs</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>