<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>2123</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Die Deutsche Seelsorgestudie 2012–2014</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Jacobs, Christoph</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">In den Jahren 2012–2014 wurde von einer interdisziplinären Forschergruppe eine flächendeckendeund repräsentative pastoralpsychologische Studie mit 8600 Personen zu Ressourcen und Belastungenin der Lebens- und Arbeitssituation bei allen seelsorglichen Berufen der deutschen Diözesen durchgeführt.Erfragt wurden Daten zu Persönlichkeit, Gesundheit, Zufriedenheit, Motivation, Belastungen,Tätigkeitsfeldern und Spiritualität. Präsentiert werden die Ziele der Studie, das methodische Konzept,das Forschungsdesign, ausgewählte Resultate und Thesen zu den Konsequenzen für die Seelsorgenden,die pastorale Organisation und die Konzeption von zukünftiger Pastoral. Von besonderer Bedeutungsind die differenzierten Ergebnisse zur Zufriedenheit, dem Wechselspiel von Person und Tätigkeitsfeldern,den verschiedenen Gesundheitsressourcen bzw. -belastungen und der Bedeutung derSpiritualität. Diskutiert werden u. a. die Notwendigkeit eines ressourcenorientierten Personaleinsatzes,diözesaner Gesundheitsförderung, Stärkung von Lebenssicherheit und spiritueller Verankerung.Between 2012 and 2014 an interdisciplinary research group carried out a comprehensive and representativepastoral-psychological study on the (psychological) resources and demands in the life andwork situation of 8,600 pastoral ministers from 22 of the 27 dioceses in Germany (diocesan clergy,religious, and lay). Data was gathered on the participants’ personalities, life and job satisfaction, motivation,health, stress factors, and areas of responsibility/activity. This article presents the aims of thestudy, its methodology and research design, and important selected findings. It indicates their significancefor pastoral care, pastoral organization, and for a vision of pastoral ministry in the future. Onthis basis it also formulates a number of “theses”. Of particular significance are the differentiated findingson the quality of life, on the interplay between the personality of the pastoral minister and her orhis domains of activity, their various health resources and stress factors, as well as the importance ofspirituality. The need to match the gifts/talents of pastoral personnel with the needs of a particularpastoral placement, to promote health initiatives at a diocesan level, to strengthen the sense of coherence,as well as the need for grounding one’s spirituality are also discussed.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Konferenz der Deutschsprachigen Pastoraltheologen und Pastoraltheologinnen e.V.</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-08-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/zpth/article/view/2123</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Zeitschrift für Pastoraltheologie (ZPTh); Bd. 37 Nr. 1 (2017): Zur Debatte gestellt: die Seelsorgestudie; 9-38</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0555-9308</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.uni-muenster.de/Ejournals/index.php/zpth/article/view/2123/2037</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>urn:nbn:de:hbz:6:3-pthi-2017-20372</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2017 Pastoraltheologische Informationen</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>